### Rami Wail Shoula

CAIRO, EGYPT ·romioshoula@gmail.com ·+201119778840

#### **PROFILE**

I am a passionate voyager in the midst of an endless ocean of knowledge. Bachelor in Nanotechnology and Nanoelectronics Engineering. Game Developer at ITI Game Development Academy (GDA). Interests include computer programming, VLSI design, EDA tools, embedded systems, Internet of things (IoT), artificial intelligence (AI), mixed signals, IC design and video game development. Recently completed Deep Learning and Accelerated Computer Science Fundamentals specializations on Coursera. Currently pursuing Game Design and Development specialization on Coursera and have successfully completed the first course.

 $Iam \it always \, keen \, on \, learning \, the \, latest \, cutting \, edge \, technologies \, and \, am \it {\it constantly} \, on \, a \, path \, of \, self-improvement.$ 

#### **EDUCATION**

## Information Technology Institute (ITI), 9 months Professional Training Program, Game Development

Nov 2021 – Present, Giza, Egypt

Courses/Programs covered include: -

- C++ Object-Oriented Programming & Data Structures
- · Visual C#.NET
- · Game Design
- UI & UXDesign
- · Computer Graphics & Shaders
- Unity3D
- Unreal Engine
- · Game Network
- · Artificial Intelligence
- · Virtual Reality

### University of Science and Technology at Zewail City (ZC: UST), B.S.C in Nanotechnology And Nano-Electronics Engineering

2016 – 2021, Giza, Egypt

GPA around 3.0

Double Focus concentration:

- · Nano-VLSI
- Nano-Fabrication and MEMS

### M.S.G British International School of Egypt, I.G.C.S.E. High School Degree

2015 - 2016, Cairo

International General Certificate of Secondary Education.

GPA 4.0. Magna cum laude.

#### DETAILS

PLACEOFBIRTH

Egypt

#### CONTACT

romioshoula@gmail.com s-romioshoula@zewailcity.edu.eg in/romioshoula github.com/romioshoula facebook.com/rami.shoula romioshoula.itch.io artstation.com/romioshoula98

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Git

Matlab/Simulink

C/C++

C#

Unity

Unreal Engine

System Verilog

Python

VHDL

HTML&CSS

Javascript

PHP

Verilog A

Cadence

Microsoft Office

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## Summer Internship, Zewail City of Science and Technology · Part-time

Jan 2020 – May 2020, Giza, Egypt

Embedded Software and Hardware Internship:

Implementing real satellite Terminal Software. GSE, MPLS, SISAP communication protocols implementation. Hardware implementation of RTEMS on Xilinx zynq-7000 FPGA board.

### Junior Researcher, Zewail City of Science and Technology Part-time

Jan 2019 – Dec 2020, Alexandria, Egypt

Design and implementation of T-shape microfluidic chip for use in micro-droplet and Janus particle formation. Simulation carried out on Cadence software. CAD tools utilized in modeling include SOLIDWORKS & CORELDRAW software. Physical design laser-printed at Egypt Japan University (E-Just) for practical testing.

## Game Developer, Information Technology Institute (ITI) · Full-time

Nov 2021 - Present, Giza, Egypt

 $9\,months\,professional\,Training\,Program\,Student.\,Game\,Programming\,Specialization\,ITI-Game\,Development\,Academy\,(GDA)$ -Intake I42. A product based program that will empower you to learn the required skills and knowledge in all aspects of Game Development from the basics to the advanced topics, from a real-world industry perspective to develop 2D, 3D and XR game applications to build a top-notch portfolio.

### EXTR A-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

### IT, Media & Marketing committee head, EUROAVIA, Zewail City

2016 – 2017, Giza, Egypt

### Committee member, IEEE, Zewail City

2016 – 2018, Giza, Egypt

#### Volunteer, Resala Charity Organization

2017 - 2018, Giza, Egypt

Volunteer for fundraising and aiding the charity organization in Cairo branch

#### **COURSES**

### Accelerated Computer Science Fundamentals Specialization, Coursera

Dec 2021

### Deep Learning Specialization, Coursera

Jan 2022

#### Game Design and Development 1: 2D Shooter, Coursera

Ian 2022

#### SOFT SKILLS

Judgement and Decision Making

Strategic Project Management

Leadership

Entrepreneurship

Communication

Teamwork

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

British Council: CIPP Outstanding Achiever 2010 - 2011

Habitudes Leadership Training 2014

2nd place in Alabakera TV Show competition 2016

### PROJECTS

ASIC Flow: Optimization of Power, Area & Frequency of a designed RTLCode using DC Compiler Tool

Two-stage Operational Amplifier using CADENCE (Pre-Layout Simulation)

Audio Amplifier Circuit

- Design and
Implementation using
Cadence (Pre-Layout
Simulation)

Analog to Digital Converter (ADC) using CADENCE (Pre-Layout Simulation)

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Undergraduate Mems and Microfluidics Graduation Project With Excellent Grade, ZC:UST under supervision of Dr. Noha Gaber

2020 - 2021, Giza, Egypt

Design of novel electrostatically powered peristaltic micropump with a single chamber and NED cantilever structure. A thorough fabrication recipe was developed. NED cantilever structure provided a permanent solution for pull-in effect in electrostatic based systems. Wide range of applications as it can be used in precise drug delivery/dosing systems, developing cooling systems for electronic systems, such as System-on-a-Chip and embedded systems, as well as Lab-on-a-Chip and testing kits. ITAC-CFP - ITIDA Funding.

# ASIC Design And Implementation Of 32 Bit Mac Unit, ZC:UST under supervision of Dr. Hassan Mostafa

2019 – 2020, Giza, Egypt

 $Cadence\ Virtuoso\ Simulation\ design\ and\ implementation\ of\ 32\ bit\ MAC\ unit\ with\ pre-and\ post-layout\ merits\ (delay,\ power\ \&area)$ 

## Analog Mixed Signals 10-bit SAR ADC, ZC:UST under supervision of Dr. R. El-Damak

2021 – 2021, Giza, Egypt

Design of a 10 bit ADC for wearable brain computer interface system using the 90 nm generic PDK on Cadence Virtuoso with 1 V supply with a 32 kHz sampling rate. Implementation of rate Successive Approximation Register (SAR) ADC, Sample and hold circuit (SHA) and Digital to Analog Converter (DAC). The ENOB and SNR are measured to be 6.7,42.22 dB respectively, giving a FOM = 2.85 pJ / Conv D step.

## Testing And Verif ication Of IP In UVM Environment, ZC:UST under supervision of Dr. Hassan Mostafa

2021 — 2021, Giza, Egypt

Implementation of Universal Verification Methodology (UVM) using UVM 1.2 package on EDA playground / System Verilog. Testing and verification of encrypted intellectual property (IP).

# C++ Connectivity Matrix and Partitioning EDA Algorithm, ZC:UST under supervision of Amr Nabil Helmy

Oct 2019, Giza, Egypt

Written a C++ program which partitions an even number of cells using Kernighan-Lin partitioning algorithm after obtaining the connectivity matrix of the cells. The input was a pin-oriented netlist, and the output clearly specified which cells belong to which block.

## C++ EDA Functional Algorithmic Project, ZC:UST under supervision of Amr Nabil Helmy

Nov 2019, Giza, Egypt

Written a C++ code to read netlist data from a text file, extract the different paths, calculate the maximum propagation delay for each node, do proper partioning, perform floor-planning and then find the longest path and determine the suitable clock period.

### **PROJECTS**

Modeling a 90-nm NMOS and PMOS With COMSOL

Diamagnetically levitated electrostatic micromotor (DLEM) model and fabrication

Temperature Sensor based on Light Transmittance inside an optical fiber using COMSOL

NMOS Transistor Fabrication using SENTAURUS

Write and develop C++ EDA tool to calculate connectivity matrix, partition, perform floorplanning and measure merits of each path

Design RF / Mixed signals LNA in Cadence and ASITIC. Merits calculated for pre- and post- (DRC, LVS and PEX) layout simulation

Adv. MEMS simulation of electrostatic microvalve

#### **LANGUAGES**

English	
Arabic	
French	
German	
Japanese	